In the previous few lectures, we looked at our decision point one, how we can select the right
AWD service.
Now we come to the second decision point, how do we select the right foundation model for
our use case.
Now in the next few lectures, we are going to focus on how do we select the right foundation
model.
Now let's start with the factors that impact the choice of our foundation models.
So the first thing we need to think about is the modality of our foundation model.
So let's say your use case is focused more on text, like text summarization, content
generation, then your foundation model should have modality as text.
Now let's say your use case is focused on advertisement and as part of that, you need to
create images, videos and so on.
Then the modality of the foundation model you select should be image.
Now there are certain scenarios like in our use case for manufacturing where we are going
to send the images as well as text to our foundation model.
Then it should support multimodal where it supports both text and image processing.
And that's sometimes called as text vision in Amazon better terms.
And then finally we have the embedding.
So there are some foundation models that support the embedding modality.
So what they do is let's say we have a text document or image, they would create a vector
representation of that image or dot of the document or image and then store.
So it's mainly used for search and retrieval process.
So based on your use case, you need to select the foundation model with right modality.
Next you should assess the task complexity of your use case.
So whether it's a use case like summarization, which is much easier or there's a lot
of reasoning involved in your use case to process the user request.
And that to a large extent will decide what kind of foundation model will you use whether
you will use a small language model or a large language model.
So usually small language models are classified which have parameters up to 8 billion and large
language models could have hundreds of billions of parameters.
So next is the context window.
So context window means what is the maximum amount of words that you can input at one point
of time to your foundation model.
So it varies between model to model and it can range anything from 8K input size token
to 200K.
So Cloud and Tropic supports 200K token.
We know 1000 tokens is approximately 750 words.
So 200K maximal token size would be about 150K words which you can send as input.
Now there could be some scenarios, let's say you are generating content.
So your input token size might be much smaller.
But there could also be scenarios, let's say we are working in the legal department of
an organization and you are and you want to summarize your contract document.
So in that case the contract document size could be in hundreds of pages.
In that scenario you might need a very, very large context window.
So that's why it's important to understand what is the context window size for a large
language model.
Okay, next one is the guard rail and safety in most foundation models.
There are some built in guard rail and additional capability around toxicity, content moderation.
So let's say you have built a generic application using the foundation model.
And now one of the end users pose a question like I want to know how I can kill someone.
So you don't want your foundation model to answer those sort of questions.
So most foundation owners have already have some form of guard rail.
So you might want to analyze what kind of guard rail are available in built as part of
the large language model.
Though you can supplement it based on your organization guidelines as well through better
guard rails and SageMaker custom guard rail, but you should also evaluate what are the
kind of guard rail available to the large language model.
Next we have the quality and accuracy of the output.
So you can use the better console to evaluate foundation models from different model providers
and see what is the kind of output it is generating for you.
You can then you can also use the bedrock model output evaluation tool to automatically
or through humans evaluate the output of different foundation model and see if the kind
of response that you are getting fits based on your use case.
Then you have cost predictability and token efficiency.
You can evaluate the cost per thousand tokens for different model providers as well
as different models from the same model provider.
And this is important because let's say you are doing a pucie, so let's say you are sending
a few 100 requests and and in bedrock each request could cost a few cents.
So it might not be a lot of cost.
But when you do that at a scale at a production grade scale where you are sending hundreds
and thousands of requests over a period of year that there could be a enormous cost difference.
So that's why you have to optimize your foundation model based on the cost per thousand
token.
Then you also need to look at regional availability and quotas.
So lot of foundation models are not available in many different regions.
You should evaluate whether that foundation model is available within your region.
And then bedrock and also set some quotas for the foundation models on number of requests
that you can make per minute in that region.
So you should look at quotas and it meets the throughput requirements of your journey application
using that foundation model.
Next and something that is really really important is latency.
So latency is really important from the end user experience perspective.
Think about using chat GPT and you pose a question and gives your response in three minutes.
So that user experience would not be great.
So that's why from the end user experience latency optimization is critical.
And there are a lot of foundation models which bedrock provides which are latency optimized
inference model and you can evaluate whether you actually need those sort of models.
And we're going to discuss latency optimize inference models later in the course.
And then we have the proprietary versus open source.
So you should always perform open source models compared to proprietary ones.
So then finally we have the language support.
So not all foundation models support all the languages.
So you should go ahead and evaluate what are the languages supported by that particular
foundation model based on your use case.
And finally in summary select the smallest safest and most cost efficient model that meets
your accuracy latency and governess requirements for your workload.
Okay.
So those are some of the factors you should think about when you are selecting the foundation
model for your use case.
That's pretty much from this lecture.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.